<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>programming on Filip Livancic</title>
    <link>https://filpill.github.io/categories/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in programming on Filip Livancic</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 21:12:42 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://filpill.github.io/categories/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building Data Pipelines With Python: Systems Perspective</title>
      <link>https://filpill.github.io/projects/data_system/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 21:12:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filpill.github.io/projects/data_system/</guid>
      <description>Summary I am always spotting oppertunities to streamline processes and alleviate the burden from our day to day work.
This article serves as an example for the wide ranging applications I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Python to automate both simple and complex tasks with high efficiency.
Data Transformation &amp;amp; Processing System These are some of the goals we are trying to achieve:
To build complete end-to-end data solutions from source to user. We want to minimise manual task inputs during the data processing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Github - Command Line Interface Procedures</title>
      <link>https://filpill.github.io/projects/github/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filpill.github.io/projects/github/</guid>
      <description>Summary The purpose of this page is to document the most common ways I interact with git and in maintaining my programs. These actions are performed via the command line as per how the tool was originally designed.
In my opinion the main benefit is the added efficiency of the scripting out the majority of the CLI commands via a series of shell scripts.
This simply allows you to direct all of your attention on creating better quality work without getting lost in a GUI most of the time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Codewars - Solving Coding Problems</title>
      <link>https://filpill.github.io/projects/codewars/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filpill.github.io/projects/codewars/</guid>
      <description>Codewars Profile Filpill - Codewars Profile
What is Codewars? A website that provides challenges for you to solve in a variety of programming languages. The higher the rank of the problem, the harder it is to solve.
Motivation Recently I was feeling inspired to try and improve my existing programming skills. I am specifically focusing on improving my fundamental knoweldge of Python.
The majority of my learning process so far has been based on my independant project based learning.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
