<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>data on Filip Livancic</title>
    <link>https://filpill.github.io/categories/data/</link>
    <description>Recent content in data on Filip Livancic</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://filpill.github.io/categories/data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chess.com API - Data Visaulisation</title>
      <link>https://filpill.github.io/projects/chess/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filpill.github.io/projects/chess/</guid>
      <description>Summary I&amp;rsquo;ve played a fair amount of chess on the chess.com platform since 2019 and fortunately all my chess data can be explored using the API endpoints documented inside the website.
I&amp;rsquo;ve was interested in seeing how my rating has changed over time from a graphical perspective.
Though, I didn&amp;rsquo;t make much improvement given that I was playing chess casuallly and was not learning chess strategy in depth.
Link to the project here: Chess.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Data Pipelines With Python: Systems Perspective</title>
      <link>https://filpill.github.io/projects/data_system/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 21:12:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filpill.github.io/projects/data_system/</guid>
      <description>Summary There are endless oppertunities to streamline processes and automate our data production tasks.
This article serves as an example for the wide ranging applications I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Python to automate both simple and complex tasks with high efficiency.
Data Transformation System These are some of the goals we are trying to achieve:
To build complete end-to-end data solutions from the data source to user. We want to minimise manual task interventions during the data processing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Valorant API - Web Scraping Project</title>
      <link>https://filpill.github.io/projects/val_scrp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filpill.github.io/projects/val_scrp/</guid>
      <description>Summary I was searching for a Valorant API to collect and analyse some of my own match data. However the developers are not providing personal API keys for this particular game.
There are some websites which are publishing the Valorant data into the public domain. I decided to scrape my own match data which is being hosted on their web clients.
Though the volume of data highlighted on the website is limited compared to the actual volume of games I&amp;rsquo;ve played.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Age of Empire 2 API - Data Visualisation</title>
      <link>https://filpill.github.io/projects/aoe2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:59:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filpill.github.io/projects/aoe2/</guid>
      <description>Summary I decided to showcase some data transformations on I game that usually play and see if I could get some cool visualisations/insights. I&amp;rsquo;m using an API to replicate a sample of data visualisations I would typically make. In my work I normally query out of a SQL database for my data ingestion but trying something new here as an experiment. This was my first time using an API to extract JSON data, but its very easy to manipulate on Python to transform into a dict/dataframe.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
