<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>design on Filip Livancic</title>
    <link>https://filpill.github.io/tags/design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in design on Filip Livancic</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://filpill.github.io/tags/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>3D Printed RC Tractor</title>
      <link>https://filpill.github.io/eng_projects/rctractor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filpill.github.io/eng_projects/rctractor/</guid>
      <description>Summary Finshed designing and building a functional RC car (which now appears to be more akin to a tractor) which is mostly 3D Printed.
The reason for the large wheels in the back is because of how I started my design process. The design was built around the gearbox. Since the gearbox ended up being very tall, I figured I would just mount some very large wheels to clear the ground.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D Printed GoPro Skateboard</title>
      <link>https://filpill.github.io/eng_projects/gopro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filpill.github.io/eng_projects/gopro/</guid>
      <description>Summary Designed a skateboard for my GoPro, experimenting with different camera perspectives; in particular with low rolling shots.
The camera mount point is not ideal as the wheels are caught in the field of view&amp;hellip;It&amp;rsquo;s not too bad, but still a little bit distracting when shooting a wide angle. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to envision this issue when you are designing it. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to get distracted with the other design elements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lithophane Lamp</title>
      <link>https://filpill.github.io/eng_projects/litho/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filpill.github.io/eng_projects/litho/</guid>
      <description>Summary Designed a 3D printed lithophane lamp in Soldworks. Main feature: Replaceable lithophanes of chosen standard of aspect ratio/dimension. Features Top/Bottom Panels retained with three M3 screws &amp;ndash; Removing the panels gives access to replacing the printed lithophane. Wiring threads through back of assembly and socket leans on back the back panel. Forward attachment clamps the socket and constrains the foward movement of the light socket with screws. I have two slightly different designs to accomadate either an E14 lamp socket or an E27 lamp socket.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D Printed Car - Bluetooth Controller Interface</title>
      <link>https://filpill.github.io/eng_projects/3dcar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filpill.github.io/eng_projects/3dcar/</guid>
      <description>Summary Personal project to design and build a 3D printed car from scratch. Project status is currently dormant as I haven&amp;rsquo;t had time to iterate over the design due to the complexity and required time investment. The project was gradually being built over the course of 2020 and 2021. Though incomplete, I may return to this project at a later stage (with a smaller scope) after finishing some other projects. The project requires some simplification for the desired goal of having a robust car design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UAV Aircraft Design</title>
      <link>https://filpill.github.io/eng_projects/uav/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filpill.github.io/eng_projects/uav/</guid>
      <description>Summary My elected project for my 4th year in University was to design and build a UAV aircraft. The design requirements were driven out from the 2017 BMFA competition (Payload Challenge). The design had to be capable of flying some circuits with varying volumes of water weighing up to 3.5kg. As project engineer, I was responsible for coordinating the technical requirements and outputs between our sub-teams. Previous Next &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; / [pdf] View the PDF file here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forward Facing Step - Particle Image Velocimetry</title>
      <link>https://filpill.github.io/eng_projects/piv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filpill.github.io/eng_projects/piv/</guid>
      <description>Summary My 3rd year project in University was to design a Forward Facing Step and perform wind tunnel experiments to analyse flow characteristics on that geometry using PIV.
Particle Image Velocimetry is a practical tool for Aerodynamics analyse flow fields without intrusions in the wind tunnel environment such as sensors or pitot probes.
In this experiment the height of the boundary layer is similarly proportioned to the height of the step.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
