<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>programming on Filip Livancic</title>
    <link>https://filpill.github.io/tags/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in programming on Filip Livancic</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://filpill.github.io/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Github - Command Line Interface Procedures</title>
      <link>https://filpill.github.io/projects/github/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filpill.github.io/projects/github/</guid>
      <description>Summary The purpose of this page is to document the most common ways I interact with git and in maintaining my programs. These actions are performed via the command line as per how the tool was originally designed.
In my opinion the main benefit is the added efficiency of the scripting out the majority of the CLI commands via a series of shell scripts.
This simply allows you to direct all of your attention on creating better quality work without getting lost in a GUI most of the time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Codewars - Solving Coding Problems</title>
      <link>https://filpill.github.io/projects/codewars/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filpill.github.io/projects/codewars/</guid>
      <description>Codewars Profile Filpill - Codewars Profile
What is Codewars? A website that provides challenges for you to solve in a variety of programming languages. The higher the rank of the problem, the harder it is to solve.
Motivation Recently I was feeling inspired to try and improve my existing programming skills. I am specifically focusing on improving my fundamental knoweldge of Python.
The majority of my learning process so far has been based on my independant project based learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Scraper - Valorant Data Analysis</title>
      <link>https://filpill.github.io/projects/val_scrp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filpill.github.io/projects/val_scrp/</guid>
      <description>Summary I was searching for a Valorant API to collect and analyse some of my own match data. However the developers are not providing personal API keys for this particular game.
There are some websites which are publishing the Valorant data into the public domain. I decided to scrape my own match data which is being hosted on their web clients.
Though the volume of data highlighted on the website is limited compared to the actual volume of games I&amp;rsquo;ve played.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Age of Empire 2 API - Data Visualisation</title>
      <link>https://filpill.github.io/projects/aoe2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:59:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filpill.github.io/projects/aoe2/</guid>
      <description>Summary I decided to showcase some data transformations on I game that usually play and see if I could get some cool visualisations/insights. I&amp;rsquo;m using an API to replicate a sample of data visualisations I would typically make. In my work I normally query out of a SQL database for my data ingestion but trying something new here as an experiment. This was my first time using an API to extract JSON data, but its very easy to manipulate on Python to transform into a dict/dataframe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D Printed Car - Bluetooth Controller Interface</title>
      <link>https://filpill.github.io/projects/3dcar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filpill.github.io/projects/3dcar/</guid>
      <description>Summary Personal project to design and build a 3D printed car from scratch. Project status is currently dormant as I haven&amp;rsquo;t had time to iterate over the design due to the complexity and required time investment. The project was gradually being built over the course of 2020 and 2021. Though incomplete, I may return to this project at a later stage (with a smaller scope) after finishing some other projects. The project requires some simplification for the desired goal of having a robust car design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2D Heat Transfer Simulation</title>
      <link>https://filpill.github.io/projects/ht_sim/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filpill.github.io/projects/ht_sim/</guid>
      <description>Summary Re-writing 2D heat transfer simulation designed in MATLAB to Python. Solved using Successive Over Relaxation Algorithm and Finite Difference Method used to capture incremental changes of temeperature on grid. Animated the heat transitions in Python at each timestep using FuncAnimation component of matplotlib. LHS boundaries on the mesh and the application of the heat input on the leftmost nodes. Heat Input lasts 2 seconds in resulting simulation before being turned off.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
