<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>python on Filip Livancic</title>
    <link>https://filpill.github.io/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in python on Filip Livancic</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://filpill.github.io/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chess.com API - Data Visaulisation</title>
      <link>https://filpill.github.io/projects/chess/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filpill.github.io/projects/chess/</guid>
      <description>Summary I&amp;rsquo;ve played a fair amount of chess on the chess.com platform since 2019 and fortunately all my chess data can be explored using the API endpoints documented inside the website.
I&amp;rsquo;ve was interested in seeing how my rating has changed over time from a graphical perspective.
Though, I didn&amp;rsquo;t make much improvement given that I was playing chess casuallly and was not learning chess strategy in depth.
Link to the project here: Chess.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Data Pipelines With Python: Systems Perspective</title>
      <link>https://filpill.github.io/projects/data_system/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 21:12:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filpill.github.io/projects/data_system/</guid>
      <description>Summary There are endless oppertunities to streamline processes and automate our data production tasks.
This article serves as an example for the wide ranging applications I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Python to automate both simple and complex tasks with high efficiency.
Data Transformation System These are some of the goals we are trying to achieve:
To build complete end-to-end data solutions from the data source to user. We want to minimise manual task interventions during the data processing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Age of Empire 2 API - Data Visualisation</title>
      <link>https://filpill.github.io/projects/aoe2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:59:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filpill.github.io/projects/aoe2/</guid>
      <description>Summary I decided to showcase some data transformations on I game that usually play and see if I could get some cool visualisations/insights. I&amp;rsquo;m using an API to replicate a sample of data visualisations I would typically make. In my work I normally query out of a SQL database for my data ingestion but trying something new here as an experiment. This was my first time using an API to extract JSON data, but its very easy to manipulate on Python to transform into a dict/dataframe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2D Heat Transfer Simulation</title>
      <link>https://filpill.github.io/projects/ht_sim/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filpill.github.io/projects/ht_sim/</guid>
      <description>Summary Re-writing 2D heat transfer simulation designed in MATLAB to Python. Solved using Successive Over Relaxation Algorithm and Finite Difference Method used to capture incremental changes of temeperature on grid. Animated the heat transitions in Python at each timestep using FuncAnimation component of matplotlib. LHS boundaries on the mesh and the application of the heat input on the leftmost nodes. Heat Input lasts 2 seconds in resulting simulation before being turned off.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forward Facing Step - Particle Image Velocimetry</title>
      <link>https://filpill.github.io/projects/piv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filpill.github.io/projects/piv/</guid>
      <description>Summary My 3rd year project in University was to design a Forward Facing Step and perform wind tunnel experiments to analyse flow characteristics on that geometry using PIV.
Particle Image Velocimetry is a practical tool for Aerodynamics analyse flow fields without intrusions in the wind tunnel environment such as sensors or pitot probes.
In this experiment the height of the boundary layer is similarly proportioned to the height of the step.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
