<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>matlab on Filip Livancic</title>
    <link>https://filpill.github.io/tags/matlab/</link>
    <description>Recent content in matlab on Filip Livancic</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://filpill.github.io/tags/matlab/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2D Heat Transfer Simulation</title>
      <link>https://filpill.github.io/page_archive/ht_sim/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filpill.github.io/page_archive/ht_sim/</guid>
      <description>Summary Re-writing 2D heat transfer simulation designed in MATLAB to Python. Solved using Successive Over Relaxation Algorithm and Finite Difference Method used to capture incremental changes of temeperature on grid. Animated the heat transitions in Python at each timestep using FuncAnimation component of matplotlib. LHS boundaries on the mesh and the application of the heat input on the leftmost nodes. Heat Input lasts 2 seconds in resulting simulation before being turned off.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UAV Aircraft Design</title>
      <link>https://filpill.github.io/eng_projects/uav/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filpill.github.io/eng_projects/uav/</guid>
      <description>Summary My elected project for my 4th year in University was to design and build a UAV aircraft. The design requirements were driven out from the 2017 BMFA competition (Payload Challenge). The design had to be capable of flying some circuits with varying volumes of water weighing up to 3.5kg. As project engineer, I was responsible for coordinating the technical requirements and outputs between our sub-teams. Previous Next &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; / [pdf] View the PDF file here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forward Facing Step - Particle Image Velocimetry</title>
      <link>https://filpill.github.io/eng_projects/piv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://filpill.github.io/eng_projects/piv/</guid>
      <description>Summary My 3rd year project in University was to design a Forward Facing Step and perform wind tunnel experiments to analyse flow characteristics on that geometry using PIV.
Particle Image Velocimetry is a practical tool for Aerodynamics analyse flow fields without intrusions in the wind tunnel environment such as sensors or pitot probes.
In this experiment the height of the boundary layer is similarly proportioned to the height of the step.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
